Courage is immortal.
Thor is a adventure, fantasy, action film directed by Kenneth Branagh.
Against his father Odin's will, The Mighty Thor - a powerful but
arrogant warrior god - recklessly reignites an ancient war.
Thor is cast down to Earth and forced to live among humans as punishment.
Once here, Thor learns what it takes to be a true hero when the most dangerous
villain of his world sends the darkest forces of Asgard to invade Earth.
Thor, played by Chris Hemsworth.
Jane Foster, played by Natalie Portman.
Loki, played by Tom Hiddleston.
Odin, played by Anthony Hopkins.
Erik Selvig, played by Stellan Skarsgård.
Darcy Lewis, played by Kat Dennings.
Thor is a 2011 American superhero film based on the
Marvel Comics character of the same name.
Produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Paramount Pictures, it is
the fourth film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
It was directed by Kenneth Branagh, written by the writing team of Ashley Edward Miller and Zack Stentz along with Don Payne, and stars Chris Hemsworth as the title character alongside
Natalie Portman, Tom Hiddleston, Stellan Skarsgård, Kat Dennings, Clark Gregg, Colm Feore, Ray Stevenson, Idris Elba, Jaimie Alexander, Rene Russo, and Anthony Hopkins.
After reigniting a dormant war, Thor is banished from Asgard to
Earth, stripped of his powers and his hammer Mjölnir.
As his brother Loki (Hiddleston) plots to take the
Asgardian throne, Thor must prove himself worthy.
Sam Raimi first developed the concept of a film adaptation based on Thor in 1991, but soon
abandoned the project, leaving it in "development hell" for several years.
During this time, the rights were picked up by various film studios until Marvel signed Mark Protosevich
to develop the project in 2006, and planned to finance and release it through Paramount.
Matthew Vaughn was assigned to direct the film for a tentative 2010 release.
However, after Vaughn was released from his holding deal in 2008, Branagh was
approached and the film's release was rescheduled to 2011.
The main characters were cast in 2009, and principal photography took
place in California and New Mexico from January to May 2010.
The film was converted to 3D in post-production.
Thor premiered in Sydney on April 17, 2011, and was released in the
United States on May 6, as part of Phase One of the MCU.
It received generally positive reviews from critics and was a
financial success, earning $449.3 million worldwide.
Three sequels have been released: Thor: The Dark World (2013), Thor:
Ragnarok (2017), and Thor: Love and Thunder (2022).
The film explores themes of new mexico, superhero,
redemption, banishment, based on comic.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.